David Padilla

Full Stack Web Developer

Portfolio davidpadilla.io GitHub github.com/dpadillajs

Advanced experience in creating the perfect UX/UI design alongside server-based operations using both relational and non-relational databases. Over 700+ contributions on GitHub building full stack web applications with goals to solve the individual needs of users today.

Successful in working both team and self-directed settings to meet coding project deadlines. Proven ability to quickly master new technologies.

Personal Info

Phone

+1 919 869 9647

Email

davidpadilla.dev@gmail.com

Address

Raleigh, NC 27615

Technical Skills

FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap 4

Material-UI

JavaScript

ES6

jQuery

Handlebars

Firebase

React

BACK END TECHNOLOGIES

Node.js

Express

NoSQL

MongoDB

Mongoose

MySQL

Sequelize

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

RESTful APIs

JSON

AJAX

Debugging Tools

Project Highlights

2019-04

Recipedia

Full Stack Web Developer

Recipedia is a MERN-stack application that makes weekly meal planning easier. Designed with the busy professional in mind, the site allows users to search for recipes, favorite them for future reference, and build a weekly menu.

- WEBSITE https://my-recipedia.com/
- KEY SKILLS Material-UI, RESTful APIs, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, React

2019-02

Schedulr

Front-end Web Developer

Schedulr is a full stack application that any company can use to schedule or manage appointments for their clients. In addition, companies may also send friendly text reminders to their client's mobile number.

- WEBSITE https://app-schedulr.herokuapp.com/
- KEY SKILLS Bootstrap 4, Handlebars, Nexmo, MySQL, Express, Node.js

2018-12

CineGrub

UX/UI Designer

CineGrub is a front-end application that seamlessly integrates the ability to find movies and restaurants nearby via zip code. Users can also save any movie or restaurant result found and send invitations to their friends.

- WEBSITE https://cinegrub.com/
- KEY SKILLS CSS Grid, JavaScript, jQuery, RESTful APIs, Google Maps, Firebase



Education

2018-10 -

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

2019-04

Coding Boot Camp - Full Stack Web Development Certification

An intensive 24 week program dedicated to building full stack web applications.



Experience

2017-08 -

Financial Associate I - Health & Welfare

2018-09

Fidelity Investments

- Investigated multiple IBM data records to uncover and fix errors, reducing resolution times by 2-3 weeks.
- Recognized by multiple achievement awards to take on more managerial duties such as peer mentorship to boost overall workflow.

2014-01 -

Scheduling Agent

2017-07

AIG VALIC

- Improved communication for over 50+ advisors and their clients, which in turn resulted in greater retirement contributions as well as client retention.
- Increased performance from both the scheduling staff and supervisor by presenting new departmental procedures and statistics through Excel.